Contact

ak5366sn@cnr.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/alkakurian (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Nursing

Telemetry

Languages

Spanish (Elementary)

English

Malayalam

Certifications

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support Experienced Provider (ACLS)

Basic Life Support

Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS)

CMSRN

FNP

Honors-Awards

Keynote Speaker

Johnson & Johnson Campaign for Nursing's Future Scholarship

The Saint Catherine Medal

Founder's Scholarship

Serviam Award for outstanding community service

Alka Joseph, MS, FNP-C, CMSRN, CBN

Hospitalist NP

United States

Summary

Experienced Acute Care Nurse Practitioner with a demonstrated history of working in the premier hospitals such as NYU Langone Health and Mount Sinai Hospital. Skilled in acute care medicine. Strong healthcare professional with a Master of Science (MS) focused in FNP and AGACNP certification.

Experience

Inpatient Physician Associates, PLLC Hospitalist NP

November 2019 - Present (8 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Provides general acute medical care of hospitalized patients at multiple facilities

- -Haven Behavioral Hospital, Frisco, TX
- -Methodist Southlake Hospital, Southlake, TX
- -Baylor Uptown Medical Center, Dallas, TX
- -North Central Surgical Center, Dallas, TX

The Back & Body Clinic Locum Nurse Practitioner May 2019 - June 2019 (2 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Provide a comprehensive list of family medicine and chiropractic services including trigger point injections and joint injections

Mount Sinai Health System

Hospitalist NP

December 2017 - February 2019 (1 year 3 months)

Works as an offsite Hospitalist NP at St.Johns Riverside Medical Center, Yonkers, NY

Inpatient medicine and treating acute, episodic, and critical disease states additional to managing chronic conditions. Proficient in Meditech EMR

NYU Langone Medical Center Senior Staff Nurse September 2013 - November 2017 (4 years 3 months) Greater New York City Area

Through a universal bed unit model, we provide for all of the patient's care needs for the entire hospitalization — from surgical step-down level of care including telemetry monitoring and continuous drips, to recovery needs such as progressive ambulation/rehabilitation and education. We provide care across the entire continuum. Proficient in EPIC EMR

The College of New Rochelle President of Student Nurses Association July 2012 - July 2013 (1 year 1 month) New Rochelle, NY

NYU Langone Medical Center Student Nurse Extern June 2012 - August 2012 (3 months) Manhattan, New York

Montefiore Health System
Summer Volunteer
June 2006 - August 2008 (2 years 3 months)
Sound Shore Medical Center, New Rochelle, NY

Interacted with patients, escorted and accompanied to appointments, provided food and hospitality to patients and their families in the ER, Organized entertainment activities, assisted with administrative tasks.

Education

The University of Texas at Arlington
Post Master's Certificate, AGACNP (2019 - 2020)

The College of New Rochelle

Master of Science (MS), FNP · (2014 - 2017)

College of New Rochelle

BSN, Health Care · (2009 - 2013)